air-quality.com 2019-06-01

# PRIVACY POLICY

### PRIVACY POLICY

**General**

Air Matters Network Pty Ltd ("Air Matters", our, us or we) operates the app **Air Matters** and the website **http://air-matters.com**. This Privacy Policy describes how we may collect, use and disclose personal information in relation to the Services, which you consent to by accessing the Services. “Personal information” means information about an identifiable individual but does not include business information.

This Privacy Policy may be supplemented or modified by consents you provide to Air Matters, and by agreements you enter into with Air Matters' services from time to time. To learn more about how we and third parties may process personal information for interest based advertising, and to opt out of such uses, please read below.

**What information is collected**

Air Matters wants to make your experiences with us satisfying and safe. Our data collection policies allow you to choose how much personal information to provide to us, and to control how we use that information. Our goal is to provide you with a satisfying experience while allowing you to control your privacy. Air Matters collects and uses information primarily to make it easier and more rewarding for you to use our services. If you choose to register with us, you may be asked at various times to provide information such as your name, email address. Customers who personalize our service come back more often - and it's the customers that visit us often who make us successful - so we do everything we can to make Air Matters your service and to give you just the content you want.

Information collected online is often defined as being either personally identifiable or anonymous:

**Personal Information** refers to information that identifies specifically who you are, such as your name, e-mail address, or mailing address. In many cases we need this information to provide the personalized or enhanced service that you have requested. We hope that, like many of our customers, you will find it beneficial to judiciously provide Information to Air Matters so that we may provide more valuable free content and products to you.

The amount of Personal Information that you choose to disclose to Air Matters is completely up to you. The only way we know something about you personally is if you register for a personalized service or send us feedback via e-mail. In other words, we will know Personal Information about you only if you choose to share this type of information with us.

**Anonymous Information** refers to information that cannot be tied back to a specific individual, we do not know your names, where your live, or your date of birth. What we collect from transactions such as this constitutes anonymous information. Some of the individuals who access our services decline to use the personalization features that are available to them, and therefore those individuals are anonymous to us and the data we collect is similarly anonymous information. Anonymous Information may be collected several ways, including through the use of cookies, web beacons or from the device that you are using.

**Registration**

We may require you to register in order to access certain features within the Services by providing us with a valid email address and certain basic demographic information such as age and gender. All such information will be treated in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. We will provide you with a key or other authentication allowing you to log-in to access the designated features. If you elect to store authentication information, such as a username and password, where others may access it, we are not responsible for any loss of personal data or other consequences if someone other than you uses that information to access our services. If you lose a device, such as a laptop, desktop, or smartphone, or a device is stolen containing your username and password, it is up to you to take all the steps necessary to protect yourself.

**Accessing and Deleting Your Information**

Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. We will respond to your access request within a reasonable timeframe.

You have the right to delete your personal data from our server by delete your account in Settings or by contacting us, cease further dissemination of the data, and potentially have third parties halt processing of the data.

**Our Policy Regarding Children**

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from or direct or target interest based advertising to anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to use our Services. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under the age of 13 may provide any personal information. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under the age of 13, please contact us.

**Automatically Collected Information**

Some information concerning your use of the Services will be collected automatically as you use them, for example:

  * Computer, device and connection information, such as browser type and version, operating system, mobile platform and other technical identifiers;

  * Location information for location-aware Services to provide you with more relevant content for where you are in the world.

  * Cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. favorite locations, unit settings etc.). Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited.

**Android App Permissions**

Some permissions are requested from the user when the app is launched for the first time:

* External Storage Permission: to save the screenshots of the app when user need to share the screenshot. Since version 4.1.8, we have changed to only ask for the permission when user use the share screenshot feature.

* Phone State Permission: to get the phone's device id, which will be saved for ads removal service. Since version 4.1.8, we have changed to generate a random device id without this Permission.

**Philips Connected Devices**

Philips have a longstanding commitment to respect the privacy of everyone they deal with including our consumers, customers and even patients. Being transparent about how they deal with personal data helps to build trust.

They have updated their privacy notice to make it easier to understand what they do with your data and what rights you have in relation to it.

They’re making these updates as new General Data protection regulation (GDPR) come into effect in the European Union, and we’re taking the opportunity to make improvements.

Nothing is changing about your current settings or how your information is processed. Rather, they improved our Privacy Notice to make it easier to read and navigate. Their Privacy Notice is meant to help you understand what Personal Data they collect, why they collect it, what they do with it, and how they protect it, as well as your individual rights.

* Philips Privacy Notice: <https://www.philips.com/a-w/privacy-notice.html>

**Third Party Analytics Tools**

Our Services may contain third party tracking and data collection and analytics tools from our service providers, examples of which include Google Analytics, Fabric by Google and Umeng. Such third parties may use cookies, APIs, and SDKs in our Services to enable them to collect and analyze user and device related data and information on our behalf. The third parties may have access to and collect data and information about you, such as your device identifier, MAC address, IMEI, locale (specific location where a given language is spoken), geo-location information, IP address, application usage, access and session times, applications present on the device or in use at a particular time on the device, and your viewing of and interactions with advertising, for the purpose of providing their services, including, for example, enabling, providing and delivering advertising as described in further detail below.

The privacy policies of our service providers may include additional terms and disclosures regarding their data collection and use practices and tracking technologies, and we encourage you to check those privacy policies to learn more about their data collection and use practices, use of cookies and other similar tracking technologies.

**Third Party Advertising Partners**

We work with a variety of advertisers, advertising networks, advertising servers, and analytics companies. These advertisers, advertising networks, advertising servers, and analytics companies use various technologies, and technologies from third party companies, to collect data in order to send (or serve) relevant ads to you and other users. These technologies may include the placement of cookies or web beacons, the use of unique or non-unique non-personal identifiers, or the use of other technologies on our Services, and these technologies may be used to track user behavior, to track how our Services are being used, and possibly to serve you more relevant ads. These targeted advertisements may appear on our Services or other services that you visit. This Privacy Policy does not cover the use of various technologies by advertisers, advertising networks, advertising servers, and analytics companies. These companies may also obtain information from services you use from other companies, including without limitation, other websites, mobile websites, mobile downloadable applications, and downloadable desktop applications, and combine that information with information they obtain through these third party technologies on our Services. You should be aware that we do not have control over these third party technologies or the information contained in them.

**Choices Regarding Targeted Advertising and Analytics**

You can exercise an opt-out for interest based advertising services on mobile applications by checking the privacy settings of your Android or iOS device and selecting "limit ad tracking" (Apple iOS) or "opt-out of interest based ads" (Android). If you would like to adjust your choices regarding the use of precise location data, you may also do so via your mobile device settings.

We also use partners to perform services for us as processors, these partners do not use your data for additional purposes and your opt-outs can also affect these partners. For more information about their privacy practices and opt-out possibilities, please visit the links below.

  * **Google**  
Privacy Policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

  * **Umeng**  
Privacy Policy: <https://www.umeng.com/policy.html>  
Opt-outs: <https://dip.umeng.com/opt_out.html>

**Social Media Services**

When creating an account with Air Matters, you have the option of signing up using Facebook, Twitter or Google+, we may also collect, use and disclose information as follows:

**Facebook** : When you choose to log in using a Facebook account, we request access to the following:

  * Access your basic information: includes name, profile picture, gender, networks, user ID, list of friends, and information you’ve shared with everyone. This is required by Facebook in order to use the Facebook login functionality. We will display your name, and potentially your profile picture, to identify you as the person who posted a comment;

  * Send e-mail: Air Matters may e-mail you directly at your e-mail address. We require an e-mail address to match your Facebook account with our user database. We may contact you directly regarding your use of the commenting feature;

  * Post to Facebook as you: We may post status messages, notes, photos, and videos on your behalf. We require this access to allow you to send comments made on our App to your own Facebook pages, allowing you to share links with your friends. Postings sent to your Facebook pages are user-generated. You may remove this permission on Facebook at any time, under Privacy Settings;

**Twitter** : When logging in using Twitter, Air Matters will automatically be allowed to: access tweets from your timeline, see who you currently follow and those who you follow in future, see updates to your profile, and post tweets for you. Air Matters may collect this information for the purpose of customizing content and the Services. In addition, Air Matters may share information (e.g. retweets/quotes, photos/videos, usernames/Twitter handles) with Twitter (e.g. primarily to promote news articles on our Websites, offer better coverage of active weather events and encourage followers to share visual content with us) to target content and advertising as described their privacy policy, accessible here: https://twitter.com/privacy, however, your personal information is not shared with Twitter.

**Google+** : Logging in using Google+ will allow Air Matters to know who you are on Google, view your email address and view your basic Google profile information (e.g. name, email address, birth date, year of birth, gender). This information is accessed by Air Matters for the purposes of customizing content and the Services for our users.

**Updates**

Air Matters may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Please check back often for any changes. By continuing to use the Services, you accept all updates to this Privacy Policy. This version was updated on May 24, 2018.

**Contact Us**

We hope this statement has been informative and clear. Please e-mail us regarding any questions or further information you may be interested in.
